victoria jeffrey

<u>http://victoriadjeffrey.com/</u> -- Denver, CO (remote work only)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER/MANAGER

Five years of software engineering experience, delivering consistently on high quality, high load enterprise software. It started as coding and planning engineering work with peers, giving feedback, and communicating with UX and Product. Now, it's more about coordinating, planning, and leading teams to execute on the work while coaching the individuals towards their goals.

Skills:

- Quick learner; great work ethic
- Able to keep track of multiple threads at once, coordinate to completion
- Golang, Ruby, Javascript, Git, Command Line, Postgres, Elasticsearch, gRPC
- Work remotely with distributed teams; open source
- Consistently goes above and beyond
- Lead by nature; grew from entry-level software dev to eng manager in four years

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CHEF SOFTWARE (remote)

ENGINEERING MANAGER (Dec 2018 – Present)

Manage teams responsible for delivering a majority of the views in Chef Automate. Work closely with product and UX to define, refine, and schedule upcoming work streams, manage the release cycle (weekly) for the product, and coordinate the triaging and resolution of incoming customer issues. Regularly join calls with customers and/or field teams to gather feedback and deepen understanding of customer issues.

- Manage two teams, for a total of ten direct reports. Engage in bi-weekly 1:1s with all my reports, ranging in seniority from principal engineer (highest) to SDE I.
- Converted teams from loose kanban style to "light-sprint" development cycles to align with the eng org, including planning meetings, backlog refinement, and retros.
- Triage product ideas and customer issues with product and ux, prioritizing and stepping in to help on the technical side with resources or direct effort when needed. Ensure status of all things is communicated up.
- Responsible for engineer growth and team health. Set goals with engineers to help drive that growth and advocate for them and their needs/wants when appropriate. Hired two engineers and onboarded them successfully into the org

CHEF SOFTWARE (remote)

ENGINEERING LEAD (June 2018 – Dec 2018)

Acted as the point of contact on day-to-day progress for the team's engineering and product managers. Managed daily standup, contributed heavily to the codebase, and ensured the day to day work the team was focused on was aligned with priorities. Given product priorities and requirements, I was responsible for breaking work down into consumable, full slice chunks. Advocated for change when needed.

CHEF SOFTWARE (remote)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER I; II (June 2015 – June 2018)

Began as an entry-level software engineer, focused on the UI, and grew to an SDE II level, working across both the UI and backend with Golang and eventually moving my focus to the backend. Demonstrated a natural ability to keep track of lots of info, communicate effectively, and break down product requirements into consumable chunks.

- Worked on a multi-page Angular app, learning the basics of front-end development while orienting myself in the Chef ecosystem.
- Working in Go with ES and Postgres, collaborated with coworkers to develop features such as on-demand scheduled scanning using Chef InSpec and integrations with cloud providers (AWS, Azure) to read in node information and execute scans.
- Completed code reviews, general testing (unit, integration, e2e), some tdd, some pairing, refactoring, code linting, cross-team api agreements and uniformity, all the usual suspects. Contributed heavily to implementing a gRPC API for the services.

UDACITY (remote)

CODE REVIEWER (Jan 2015 – June 2015)

Selected for excellent performance in class, I was one of the very first Udacity Code Reviewers. For each project submission, I do both a thorough code review and project evaluation. Provided actionable and helpful feedback to students, researching additional resources and providing extra help when needed, while fine-tuning my own coding (and decoding) skills.

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

Hobart and William Smith Colleges

B.A. Linguistics, 2007 Minor in Ancient Greek

Udacity Nanodegree

Front-End Web Development May 2015